Guide to the Propaganda Poster Collection 1914-1996
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Series 2: Propaganda Posters (United States),World War I, circa 1914-1920
  - Subseries 2.4: Financial Aid: War Bonds, 1914-1919
    - And They Thought We Couldn't Fight, circa 1918; English; 76.5 x 103 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Clyde Forsythe. Ketterlinus, Philadelphia. (Folder 25, Item 110)
      Advertisement for Victory Liberty Loan. Graphic shows a soldier on the battlefield holding three German helmets.
    - Must Children Die and Mothers Plead in Vain?, circa 1917-1918; English; 75 x 100 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: The Sackett & Wilhelms Corporation, N.Y. (Folder 25, Item 111)
      Public endorsement of Liberty Bonds showing and image of a mother clutching her children to her side as she reaches out with a pleading gesture.
    - Clear The Way!!, circa 1917-1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Howard Chandler Christy. Niagra Lithograph Co. Buffalo, New York. (Folder 26, Item 112)
      Advertisement for Fourth Liberty Loan. Graphic shows woman in Grecian dress and laurel wreath pointing across the ocean above the busy deck of a naval vessel.
    - You Buy a Liberty Bond Lest I Perish, 1917; English; 50 x 76 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Charles Raymond Macauley. (Folder 26, Item 113)
      Advertisement for Liberty Bonds. Graphic shows a cartoon depiction of the Statue of Liberty pointing sternly at the viewer.
    - Remember Belgium, 1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Ellsworth Young. United States Printing & Lithograph Co. (Folder 26, Item 114)
      Advertisement for Fourth Liberty Loan. Graphic shows a Prussian soldier dragging a woman through a town set on fire.
    - That Liberty Shall Not Perish From The Earth, 1918; English; 75 x 102.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Ioseph Pennell Del. Ketterlinus, Phila. Imp. (Folder 26, Item 115)
      Advertisement for Fourth Liberty Loan. Graphic uses bright orange to give the illusion of New York Harbor in flames and the Statue of Liberty destroyed.
    - They Kept The Sea Lanes Open, 1918; English; 98 x 73.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: L. A. Shafer. Niagara Litho. Co. Buffalo, New York. Designed and engraved by the W. F. Powers Co. Litho., N.Y. (Folder 26, Item 116)
      Advertisement for Victory Liberty Loan. Graphic depicts a U.S. Navy ship halting an enemy submarine while a large unarmed passenger liner goes by.
    - For Victory, Buy More Bonds, 1918; English; 140.5 x 87.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: J. Scott Williams. The Morgan Lithograph Company. (Folder 26, Item 117)
      Advertisement for Fourth Liberty Loan. Graphic shows Columbia going into battle alongside the United States flag and bald eagle. In the background, soldiers march under a dark clouded sky.
    - Provide The Sinews Of War: Buy Liberty Bonds, 1918; English; 53 x 51 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Joseph Pennell. Heywood Strasser & Voigt Lithograph Co. N.Y. Imp. (Folder 27, Item 118)
      Charcoal sketch featuring image of docked naval vessel used as an advertisement to encourage Americans to buy war bonds.
    - Invest, circa 1918; English; 49 x 74 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Printed by the Strobridge Lithograph Company, Cincinnati. (Folder 27, Item 119)
      Poster reads, "Invest" under a large blue "V" for victory.
    - Come On!, 1918; English; 49 x 73 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Walter Whitehead. Printed by the Strobridge Lithograph Company, Cincinnati. (Folder 27, Item 120)
      Advertisement for Liberty Bonds. Graphic shows an American soldier standing over a fallen Prussian soldier.
    - Buy Liberty Bonds, circa 1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: American Lithographic Co. (Folder 27, Item 121)
      Advertisement for Liberty Bonds. Offers a quotation from Abraham Lincoln that reads, "That government of the people, by the people, for the people shall not perish from the earth." The portrait of Lincoln, in profile, resembles that found on a penny. A re
    - Hun or Home?, circa 1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Henry Raleigh. Printed by Edwards & Deutsch Lithograph Company, Chicago. (Folder 27, Item 122)
      Advertisement for Liberty Bonds. Graphic is a reproduction of a pastel drawing depicting a woman and child being chased by a dark figure wearing an enemy soldier helmet.
    - The Hun--His Mark--Blot It Out, 1918; English; 70.5 x 105.5; Creator/Publisher: J. Allen St. John. Printed by Edwards & Deutsch Lithograph Company, Chicago. (Folder 27, Item 123)
      Advertisement for Liberty Bonds. Features a red handprint symbolizing the Hun's "mark."
    - Keep These Off The U.S.A., circa 1917; English; 73.5 x 100.5 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: John Norton. The Strobridge Lithograph Company, Cincinnati & New York. (Folder 27, Item 124)
      Advertisement for Liberty Bonds. Features a pair of blood soaked Prussian boots.
    - Buy Bonds: Third Liberty Loan, circa 1914-1918; English; 14 x 14 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Unidentified (Folder 28, Item 125)
      This advertisement for government bonds from Third Liberty Loan is a window sticker designed to adhere to a glass surface when moistened. (2 copies)
    - Ring Me Again, circa 1914-1918; English; 20 x 29 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Patent applied for by R. E. Devnex, Cleveland, Ohio. (Folder 28, Item 126)
      This advertisement for government bonds from Third Liberty Loan is a cut-out in the shape of the Liberty bell and is designed to hang from a doorknob.
    - My Daddy Bought Me a Government Bond, 1918; English; 51 x 76 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Henry Raleigh. Printed by the United States Printing and Lithograph Company, New York. (Folder 28, Item 127)
      Advertisement for Third Liberty Loan. Image shows a young girl clutching a government bond. (2 copies)
    - Weapons For Liberty, circa 1917; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: J. C. Leyendecker. American Lithographic Co. N.Y. (Folder 28, Item 128)
      Advertisement for the Third Liberty Loan Campaign for the Boy Scouts of America. Image shows Boy Scout lifting up sword to Columbia with the inscription "Be Prepared."
    - Over The Top For You, circa 1918; English; 50.5 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Sidney H. Riesenberg. Ketterlinus, Philadelphia. (Folder 28, Item 129)
      Advertisement for Third Liberty Loan. Image shows American soldier climbing over the crest of a hill holding the American flag.
    - Remember! The Flag of Liberty, Support It!, circa 1918; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Heywood Strasser & Voigt Lithograph Co. N.Y. (Folder 28, Item 130)
      Advertisement for U.S. Government Bonds from Third Liberty Loan. Graphic shows immigrants on a ship, with a United States flag in the background.
    - Halt the Hun!, circa 1918; English; 49.5 x 74 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Henry Raleigh. Printed by Edwards & Deutsch Lithograph Company, Chicago. (Folder 28, Item 131)
      Advertisement for U.S. Government Bonds from Third Liberty Loan. Graphic is a print of pastel drawing of an Allied soldier protecting a woman and her child from an enemy soldier. (2 copies)
    - Ring It Again, circa 1917; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Printed by Sackett & Wilhelms Corporation, New York. (Folder 28, Item 132)
      Advertisement for U.S. Government Bonds from Third Liberty Loan. Graphic shows the Liberty Bell above a scene depicting colonial Philadelphia. (2 copies)
    - Are You 100% American?, 1918; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Stern. Printed by Sackett & Wilhelms Corporation, New York. (Folder 29, Item 133)
      Advertisement for government bonds from Third Liberty Loan, urging Americans to demonstrate their patriotism through the purchase of bonds. Graphic shows an eagle flanked by two U.S. flags and two smoking cannons. (2 copies)
    - Good Bye, Dad, I'm Off To Fight For Old Glory, 1918; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Laurence S. Harris. Sackett & Wilhelms Corp. N.Y. (Folder 29, Item 134)
      Advertisement for U.S. Government Bonds from Third Liberty Loan. Graphic shows soldier saying farewell to his father while encouraging him to buy government bonds.
    - To Make The World A Decent Place To Live In, circa 1918; English; 141.5 x 91 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Herbert Paus. Printed by Heywood Strasser & Voigt Lithograph Company, New York. (Folder 29, Item 135)
      Advertisement for U.S. Government Bonds from Third Liberty Loan. Graphic shows soldiers fighting under an orange sky.
    - Fight Or Buy Bonds: Third Liberty Loan, 1917; English; 75.5 x 100 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Howard Chandler Christy. Printed by Forbes, Boston. (Folder 29, Item 136)
      Advertisement for U.S. Government Bonds from Third Liberty Loan. Graphic shows depiction of Columbia leading American troops into battle. (2 copies)
    - My Soldier, 1917; English; 69.5 x 102.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: H.H. Green. Printed by The Matthews-Northrup Works, Buffalo, Cleveland, and New York. (Folder 29, Item 137)
      Advertisement for U.S. Government Bonds from Third Liberty Loan. Graphic shows mother and child praying for a soldier serving overseas with the words to the prayer printed below the image. Background consists of a blue band on top with red and white strip
  - Subseries 2.5: Financial Aid: United War Work Campaign, Y.M.C.A, Y.W.C.A; 1914-1919
    - See Him Through, 1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Burton Rice. American Lithographic Co., N.Y. United War Work Campaign. (Folder 30, Item 138)
      Issued by the United War Work Campaign, issued by the National Catholic War Council Knights of Columbus. Graphic shows a senior soldier ordering infantrymen onto the battlefield.
    - Songs of Today & Yesterday, circa 1914-1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Printed by Heywood Strasser & Voigt Litho. Co. N.Y. United War Work Campaign. (Folder 30, Item 139)
      Issued by the United War Work Campaign. Graphic shows elderly woman playing the piano for a group of men in sailor uniforms. The phrase "Songs of Today & Yesterday" appears below image.
    - Invitations to Homes and Entertainments, circa 1914-1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Printed by Heywood Strasser & Voigt Litho. Co. N.Y. United War Work Campaign. (Folder 30, Item 140)
      Issued by the United War Work Campaign. Graphic shows servicemen and a woman seated at a table, viewing correspondence.
    - A Club Dinner, circa 1914-1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Printed by Heywood Strasser & Voigt Litho. Co. N.Y. United War Work Campaign. (Folder 30, Item 141)
      Issued by the United War Work Campaign. Graphic shows a club dinner at an Asian restaurant.
    - Oh Boy! That's the Girl!, 1918; English; 76 x 102 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: George Mather Richards. Sackett & Wilhelms Corporation, N.Y. United War Work Campaign. (Folder 30, Item 142)
      Issued by the United War Work Campaign. Graphic shows woman in uniform carrying a tray of doughnuts for the soldiers as part of a service provided by the Salvation Army. (2 copies)
    - Keep'em Smiling!, 1918; English; 75.5 x 105.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: M. Leone Bracker. United War Work Campaign. (Folder 30, Item 143)
      Issued by the United War Work Campaign. Graphic shows three servicemen smiling together. Phrase at bottom of page reads, "Morale is winning the war."
    - Lend Your Strength to the Red Triangle, circa 1914-1918; English; 49.5 x 68 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Gil Spear. United War Work Campaign. Y.M.C.A. (Folder 31, Item 144)
      Issued by the United War Work Campaign in support of the Y.M.C.A. to encourage worker participation in the war effort. Graphic depicts a metal worker lifting a large block labeled with a red Y.M.C.A. symbol. Appearing in the background is a Y.M.C.A. offic
    - For Your Boy, 1918; English; 49.5 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Arthur William Brown. Y.M.C.A. (Folder 31, Item 145)
      Advertisement for the Y.M.C.A. with a graphic portraying a Y.M.C.A. officer giving a cup of coffee to a soldier.
    - In Service for the Girls of the World, 1919; English; 50.5 x 76 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Neysa Moran McMein. Y.W.C.A. (Folder 31, Item 146)
      Poster supporting the Y.W.C.A. Graphic shows a girl standing in front of the Y.W.C.A. emblem.
    - His Home Over There, circa 1914-1918; English; 69.5 x 102.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Albert Herter. Stamped by the Committee on Public Information, Division of Pictorial Publicity. (Folder 31, Item 147)
      Advertising poster for the United War Work Campaign, featuring the symbols for the Y.M.C.A. and the Y.W.C.A. Graphic shows soldiers coming out of the snow and into the Y.M.C.A.
    - One of the Thousand Y.M.C.A. Girls in France, 1918; English; 107 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Neysa Moran McMein. Grinnell Litho. Co. Inc. N.Y. United War Work Campaign. Y.M.C.A. (Folder 31, Item 148)
      Advertising poster for the United War Work Campaign fundraiser in November of 1918. Graphic shows a female Y.M.C.A. officer holding a stack of books in one hand and a cup of coffee in the other. (2 copies)
    - For Every Fighter a Woman Worker, circa 1918; English; 75.5 x 103 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Adolph Treidler. American Lithographic Co., N.Y. United War Work Campaign. Y.W.C.A. (Folder 31, Item 149)
      Advertising poster for the United War Work Campaign in support of the Y.W.C.A. Graphic shows a woman in work clothes holding an airplane in one hand and a bomb in the other. The message at the bottom says, "Care for her through the Y.W.C.A."
    - Your Boy, Your Red Cross and France, 1918; English; 35.5 x 53 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher:War Council of the American Red Cross. (Folder 31, Item 149.1)
      Propaganda poster featuring four illustrations of women from the Red Cross assisting soldiers. The largest graphic at the bottom of the poster portrays a Red Cross nurse assisting a wounded soldier write a letter home.
    - [Photograph of Marshal Ferdinand Foch], circa 1917-1918; English; 40 x 52.5 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher:Alco-Gravure. (Folder 31, Item 149.2)
      Poster depicting an image of Marshal Ferdinand Foch, the Commander in Chief of the Allied Armies.
    - Why Germany Wants Peace, circa 1918; English; 52 x 77.5 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Unidentified (Folder 31, Item 149.3)
      An explanation for Americans as to why the country entered into the war, and why the conflict continues. Offers a list of publications that provide this information.
    - Men Wanted for the Army, 1914; English; 75.5 x 102.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Unidentified (Folder 31, Item 149.4)
      Propaganda poster illustrating a group of soldiers carrying their weapons while running through a field.
    - Going-Going-Gone!, circa 1918; English; 78 x 106 cm. Black and white with orange accents.; Creator/Publisher:Aviation Section, Signal Corps. (Folder 31, Item 149.5)
      Recruitment poster for the American Air Service. Features a large graphic of an orange arrow pointing upward, and a photograph of mechanics working on a plane. Local Note - due to this poster's large physical size, it is stored at the end of the collectio
- Series 3: Propaganda Posters (United States),World War II, 1939-1949
  - Subseries 3.1: Food and Resource Conservation, 1939-1945
    - Uncle Sam Needs You to Can the Fighting Foods, circa 1939-1945; English; 43 x 58 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: National Canners Association, Washington, D.C. Printed by Stecher-Traung Lithograph Corporation, Rochester, N.Y. San Francisco, Calif. (Folder 32, Item 150)
      Poster issued by the National Canners Association to encourage American citizens to help can the crops to be sent to troops overseas. Graphic shows depiction of Uncle Sam with two teenagers.
    - Grow Your Own, Can Your Own, 1943; English; 40.5 x 57 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Alfred Parker. Division of Public Inquiries, Office of War Information, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 32, Item 151)
      Government issued poster endorsing the practice of growing and canning one's own produce in order to conserve food for the soldiers. Graphic shows a mother and daughter in matching aprons canning various foods.
    - America Has Plenty of Food, circa 1939-1945; English; 63.5 x 96.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Image initialed "G.S." Lithographed in U.S.A. by Polygraphic Company of America, Inc., New York City. (Folder 32, Item 152)
      Poster issued by the U.S. Department of Agriculture to reassure the public that the land is still producing plenty of food. Graphic shows a healthy American family in front of a background featuring scenes of full grain silos and other depictions of prosp
    - Plant a Victory Garden, 1943; English; 55.5 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Division of Public Inquiries, Office of War Information, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 32, Item 153)
      Government issued poster endorsing the practice of planting a private garden to make rations go further. Graphic shows a family working in the soil and a small child is shown looking into a basket full of vegetables.
    - Work on a Farm...This Summer, 1943; English; 40.5 x 57 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Spencer Douglass Crockwell. Division of Public Inquiries, Office of War Information, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 32, Item 154)
      Government issued poster for the recruitment of young Americans into the U.S. Crop Corps. Graphic shows a teen-aged boy and girl in farming clothes carrying a basket of vegetables.
    - Safe Water on the Farm, 1943; English; 55.5 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Image signed "Robbins." Federal Security Agency, U.S. Public Health Service. U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington, D.C. (Folder 32, Item 155)
      Poster issued by the U.S. Public Health Service to serve as a reminder to farming communities to check their local water supply. Graphic shows a small boy drinking water from a private well.
    - Going Our Way?, 1945; English; 47 x 66 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Anton Bruehl. U.S. Crop Corps. Office of War Information for the War Food Administration. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 32, Item 156)
      Advertising poster for the U.S. Crop Corps to encourage young Americans to help the war effort by becoming Victory Farm volunteers. Graphic shows a boy and girl smiling and carrying farming tools.
    - Grow Your Own, circa 1939-1945; English; 55.5 x 81 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Secretary, U.S. Department of Agriculture. Lithographed in United States of America. (Folder 32, Item 157)
      Poster issued by the U.S. Department of Agriculture for the endorsement of growing one's own fruits and vegetables. Beneath the title appears the slogan, "Food Will Win the War and Write the Peace." Also appearing at the bottom of the poster is the messag
    - Pitch in and Help!, 1944; English; 50.5 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Hubert Morely. Women's Land Army of the U.S. Crop Corps. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 32, Item 158)
      Advertising poster for the Women's Land Army to encourage women across America to join in growing crops in place of farmers who enlisted in the military.
    - Fish is a Fighting Food, 1943; English; 50.5 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Henry Koerner. Division of Public Inquiries, Office of War Information, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 33, Item 159)
      Government issued poster illustrating the need for fishing companies to catch more fish in support of the war effort. Graphic shows fishermen hauling buckets of fish onto a wooden dock.
    - Lick The Platter Clean, 1944; English; 36 x 50 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: War Food Administration. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 33, Item 160)
      Government issued poster featuring an illustration of nursery rhyme characters Jack Sprat and his wife holding up a clean platter above the words "Don't Waste Food."
    - For Gunpowder, Save Waste Fats, circa 1939-1945; English; 75 x 11.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Unknown (Folder 33, Item 161)
      Government issued poster encouraging citizens to donate waste fats to their local meat dealer in order to use them in gunpowder production. Graphic shows soldiers positioning an enormous gun toward the viewer.
    - Save Waste Fats For Explosives, 1943; English; 50.5 x 70.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Henry Koerner. Division of Public Inquiries, Office of War Information, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 33, Item 162)
      Government issued poster encouraging citizens to donate waste fats to their local meat dealer in order to use them in the production of explosives. Graphic shows a skillet pouring grease into an explosion with bombs coming out of it. (2 copies)
    - Prepare for Winter Now!, 1945; English; 35.5 x 28 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Distributed by Office of War Information. Solid Fuels Administration For War, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 34, Item 163)
      Government issued poster advertising different ways to prepare homes for winter in order to conserve fuel for the troops. Graphic shows illustration of a house with conservation suggestions listed to the left.
    - Don't Shiver Next Winter...Order Coal Now!, 1944; English; 46.5 x 66 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Egmont Arens. Solid Fuels Administration For War, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 34, Item 164)
      Poster issued by the Solid Fuels Administration For War telling the public to order coal early for winter due to the scarcity of fuel caused by the war. Graphic shows a cartoon depiction of a penguin with a shovel and a red scarf shivering in the snow.
    - War Shipments Mean Less Fuel For All, 1943; English; 56 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Division of Public Inquiries, Office of War Information, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 34, Item 165)
      Government issued poster instructing the public to dress warmly indoors and try to avoid getting sick in order to conserve fuel. Graphic shows a pair of red long underwear holding a large yellow sign.
    - Your Government Warns, Prepare for Winter Now!, 1944; English; 51 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Solid Fuels Administration For War, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 34, Item 166)
      Government issued poster advertising different ways to prepare homes for winter in order to conserve fuel for the troops. Graphic shows small illustrations of scenes demonstrating ways to save fuel with directions printed to the right.
    - Don't Let This Happen To You!, 1944; English; 50.5 x 71 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Daniel Robert Fitzpatrick. Solid Fuels Administration For War, Washington, D.C. U.S. Government Printing Office. (Folder 34, Item 167)
      Poster issued by the Solid Fuels Administration For War telling the public to order coal early for winter due to the scarcity of fuel caused by the war. Graphic shows an empty store room with a shovel in the corner and the last few pieces of coal arranged
    - How To Keep Warm With Less Fuel This Winter, circa 1939-1945; English; 51 x 71 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Office of War Information. (Folder 34, Item 168)